Register of the Štefan Osuský Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Speeches and Writings, 1916-1971. (Box 32-68)
  - "Ve Francii," n.d. (Folder 57: 8)
  - "Výklad Dr. Ripky ve Státní rade 4. března 1942," n.d. (Folder 57: 9)
  - "Výročie tragickej smrti generála Štefánika," n.d. (Folder 57: 10)
  - "Westernisers," n.d. (Folder 57: 11)
  - "Westernism," n.d. (Folder 57: 12)
  - "Westernism in Practice," n.d. (Folder 57: 13)
  - "What Is the European Man?" n.d. (Folder 57: 14)
  - "Where Great Britain Was and Whither She Was Tending," n.d. (Folder 57: 15)
  - "Who Will Unify Europe: Soviets or Atlantic Community?" n.d. (Folder 57: 16)
  - "Why the Germans Are not Human," n.d. (Folder 57: 17)
  - "Why So Much Falsehood?" n.d. (Folder 57: 18)
  - "Will the Home Front Obey Beneš' Order?" n.d. (Folder 57: 19)
  - "La Yougoslavie titoïste," n.d. (Folder 57: 20)
  - "Že vraj on muzikant," n.d. (Folder 57: 21)
  - "Zur Gegenwärtigenlage der Südetendeutschen Volksgruppe," n.d. (Folder 57: 22)
  - Osuský's statement on immigration, Restriction of Immigration, Hearings Before the Committee on Immigration and Naturalization, 1916 January 21 (Folder 57: 23)
  - "Geographical Determinism," 1918. (Folder 57: 24)
  - Magyars et pangermanistes, Bossard, Paris, 1918. (Folder 57: 25)
    Holograph in English and printed copy in French
  - "The Ukraine Mission, 1918 September 2. (Folder 57: 26)
  - "Between Serbia and Italy," 1918 September 27. (Folder 57: 27)
  - "Observations on Professor Herz's Memorandum," 1918 September 30. (Folder 57: 28-29)
  - "La Russie blanche réoccupée par les bolchewiki," 1918 October 1. (Folder 57: 30)
  - "Bulgarian Surrender," 1918 October 2. (Folder 57: 31)
  - "The Interior Political Situation of Italy," 1918 October 12. (Folder 57: 32)
  - "The Relations Between the Serbs, Croats and Slovenes at Home," 1918 November 8. (Box-folder 58: 1)
  - Le traité franco-tchécoslovaque, Comité National d'Etudes, 1924 February 4. (Folder 58: 2)
  - George D. Herron: Dovernik Wilsonov počas vojny, Brno, 1925. (Folder 58: 3)
  - "La Tchécoslovaquie dans l'Europe de demain," Le flambeau, 1930 June. (Folder 58: 4)
  - "Kriza člověka: Pramen dnešných svetových ťažkostí," lecture, Košice, Czechoslovakia, 1931 November 5. (Folder 58: 5)
  - La genèse de la Petite Entente, 1932. (Folder 58: 6)
  - Three lectures addressed to Slovak college students, Svaz slovenského studenstva, Bratislava, 1932. (Folder 58: 7)
    Typescript and clippings
  - Postavení Slovanů v mezinárodní politice, speech, Mladá Boleslav, 1933 April. (Folder 58: 8)
  - Malá dohoda, Praha, 1933 May. (Folder 58: 9)
  - "La position de l'Europe Centrale dans la politique européenne," speech, Centre Européen de la Dotation Carnegie, Paris, 1933 June 16. (Folder 58: 10)
  - Reparace, Praha, 1934. (Folder 58: 11)
  - Speech commemorating M. R. Štefánik, 1934 May. (Folder 58: 12)
  - "Edvard Beneš: Masarykovo pojetí ideje národní a problém jednoty československé," speech, 1935 May 4. (Folder 58: 13)
  - Speech on the occasion of the radio broadcast to France of Smetana's Opera 'Libuše,' 1935 October 28. (Folder 58: 14)
  - "L'Europe centrale et l'avenir du système collectif," Politique étrangère, Paris, 1936. (Folder 58: 15)
  - Společnost národů, Brno, 1936. (Folder 58: 16)
  - Speech when awarded the degree of Docteur Honoris Causa, Faculty of Law, Université de Dijon, France, 1936 February 5. (Folder 59: 1)
  - "La réforme de la Société des Nations," L'esprit international, Paris, 1936 July 1. (Folder 59: 2)
  - "Le problème des matières premières et son influence sur le destin de l'Europe," conference paper, Académie Diplomatique Internationale, Monde slave, Paris, 1937 May. (Folder 59: 3)
  - "Société des Nations ou alliances," conference paper, Société des Anciens Elèves et Elèves de l'Ecole Libre des Sciences Politiques, Paris, 1937 May 12. (Folder 59: 4)
    Printed copy (in French)
  - "The Problem of Central Europe and the Peace," 1938? (Folder 59: 5)
  - "Adolf Hitler a náš odboj," radio address, Czechoslovak Radio, 1939? (Folder 59: 6)
  - "La Tchéco-Slovaquie persiste," 1939? (Folder 59: 7)
  - Note on Bechyně, Rudolf, article, published in Nová Svoboda, 1939, August/September, regarding the Czechoslovak general's speech to Czechoslovak volunteers in a camp near Cracow. (Folder 59: 8)
    Holograph and typescript, 1939?
  - "O záchraně Slovákov," 1939? (Folder 59: 9)
  - Radio address on the fate of Czechoslovakia and Hitlerism, Czechoslovak Radio? 1939? (Folder 59: 10)
  - "La campagne de paix," 1939. (Folder 59: 11)
  - Česko-Slovensko a jeho budúcnost: Články a reči, Paris, 1939
    - Holograph and typescript in Slovak ("Slováci a Češi") (Folder 59: 12)
    - Typescript in Czech ("Česko-Slovensko a jeho budoucnost") (Folder 59: 13)
    - Typescript in Czech and Slovak of entire work (Folder 59: 14)
    - Printed copy (Folder 59: 15)
  - "The Slovaks," 1939. (Folder 59: 16)
  - "La pénétration économique de l'Allemagne en Bohême et en Moravie," 1939 April? (Folder 59: 17)
  - Speech on Hitler's occupation of Czechoslovakia, Congress of Czechs and Slovaks, 1939 April 30. (Folder 59: 18)
  - Speech, American Club, 1939 September 28. (Folder 59: 19)
  - "La Tchéco-Slovaquie renaît Sa résistance à l'oppression allemande," Notre combat, 1939 October 27. (Folder 59: 20)
  - "Nouvelles du Protectorat," 1939 November 15. (Folder 59: 21)
  - Speech on mobilization of the Czecho-Slovak army in France, 1939 November 24? (Folder 59: 22)
  - "Slovenská Vola," Československý Boj, 1939 December 2. (Folder 59: 23)
    Printed copy (in Slovak)
  - Radio Christmas address, 1939 December 24. (Folder 59: 24)
  - "Výklad Dra. Štefana Osuského, správce věcí zahraničních, v Československom národnom výbore o možnostiach stredoeuropskej federácie dna 16. Januara 1940 v Paříži," 1940 January 16. (Folder 59: 25)
  - "La Tchécoslovaquie aujourd'hui et demain," speech, Cercle Métropolitain, 1940 January 24. (Folder 59: 26)
  - Speech, l'Institut d'Etudes Slaves, Université de Paris, 1940 March 7. (Folder 59: 27)
  - "Pokoj mrtvým," 1940 April 10. (Folder 59: 28)
  - "France," speech, Oxford University, 1940 August 8. (Folder 59: 29)
  - "General Organization," 1940 November. (Folder 59: 30)
  - Speech, opening of the exhibition of Czech national art, Galerie des Beaux-Arts, Paris? 1940 December 2. (Folder 59: 31)
  - "Czechoslovakia," 1941?
    - Correspondence (Folder 59: 32)
    - Typescript drafts of intended book (Folder 59: 33-34)
  - Letters to the editor, The New Statesman and Nation, 1941. (Box-folder 60: 1)
  - Letters to the editor, The New York Herald Tribune, 1941-1953. (Folder 60: 2)
  - Letters to the editor, The Times, 1941-1956. (Folder 60: 3)
  - "Kissovi v Bratislavě," 1941 January 27. (Folder 60: 4)
  - "Renegates of the Nation Condemned," 1941 February 21. (Folder 60: 5)
  - "Poznámky Dra. Štefana Osuského k 'Mírovým cílům československým prezidenta Dr Edvarda Beneše," 1941 March 8. (Folder 60: 6)
    Typescript (in Slovak). Includes Edvard Beneš' typescript, "Mírové cíle československé" (in Czech) and correspondence with Edvard Beneš
  - "Note on France," 1941 June 11. (Folder 60: 7)
  - "Hitler's Game in Europe," 1941 June 17. (Folder 60: 8)
  - "Legal and Political Effects of the Germano-Turkish Treaty of Friendship, dated June 18th, 1941," 1941 June 20. (Folder 60: 9)
  - Note on the post-war political status of Eastern Europe, 1941 August 5. (Folder 60: 10)
  - "Principles of the Atlantic Declaration," 1941 August 20 (Folder 60: 11)
    Typescript and correspondence
  - "Czechoslovakia To-Morrow," The New Commonwealth Quarterly, 1941 October. (Folder 60: 12)
  - "Liberty or Uniformity in Eastern Europe," Contemporary Review, 1941 November. (Folder 60: 13)
  - "Národná sloboda proti národnej jednotvárnosti vo východnej Europe," 1941 November 6. (Folder 60: 14)
  - "Poland and Czechoslovakia," 1941 November 8. (Folder 60: 15)
  - Pravda víťazí: Pohlad do zrkadla druhého odboja, London, 1942. (Folder 60: 16)
  - ízená demokracie pri práci, London, 1942. (Folder 60: 17)
    Typescript and printed copy (in Slovak)
  - "Does Sovereignty Exist to Preserve National Life or to Strangle It?" The Highway, 1942 March. (Folder 60: 18)
    Typescript and printed copy
  - "Historical Background," lecture (part of a series of lectures on the Reconstruction of Europe), 1942 May 3. (Folder 61: 1)
  - "Některé aktuelní problémy rekonstrukční," lecture, Hospodářská poradna, Československý Institut, 1942 July 13. (Folder 61: 2)
  - Remarks on "Authenticity of Dr. Beneš' Letter Quoted by Frank," 1942 October. (Folder 61: 3)
  - "Mravnost a pravda," analysis of Beneš' speech at the Czech National Council meeting, 1942 November? (Folder 61: 4)
  - Letters to the editor, Čechoslovák, 1942-1964. (Folder 61: 5)
  - Beneš a Slovensko, London, 1943 (in English and Slovak). (Folder 61: 6)
  - Triedenie duchov nastalo, London, 1943 (in Slovak)
    - Holograph (Folder 61: 7)
    - Printed copy (Folder 61: 8)
  - "Dr. Beneš' Constitutional Presidency?" 1943 January 18. (Folder 61: 9)
  - "Dr. Beneš' Authoritative Regime," 1943 January 23. (Folder 61: 10)
  - "The Polish-Czechoslovak Confederation," London, 1943 January 26. (Folder 61: 11)
  - Speech upon the fourth anniversary of Hitler's occupation of Czechoslovakia, Friends of the Polish-Czechoslovak Union, London, 1943 March 15. (Folder 61: 12)
  - "Great and Small Nations," Free Europe, 1943 April 9. (Folder 61: 13)
  - "Problem unji polsko-czechoslowackiej," speech, Komitet Wymiany Mysli i Pogladow, 1943 April 14. (Folder 61: 14)
  - "Poland and Czechoslovakia," Wiadomosci Polskie, 1943 April 25. (Folder 61: 15)
  - "Observations to the Statement against Slovak Autonomy Made by the Czechoslovak Government in London over the B.B.C.," 1943 July 10-12. (Box-folder 62: 1)
    Typescript. Includes holograph and typescript entitled "Comments on Dr. Beneš' Official Policy Regarding Slovakia" (in English and Slovak)
  - Note on events of March 1939, 1943 October 13. (Folder 62: 2)
  - Letters to the editor, Slovak News, 1943. (Folder 62: 3)
  - Letters to the editor, The Norseman, 1943-1944. (Folder 62: 4)
  - Letters to the editor, Slovenský Hlásník, 1943-1948. (Folder 62: 5)
  - Miscellaneous letters to the editors, 1943-1971. (Folder 62: 6)
  - "Double Standard of Morality," The Norseman, London, 1944 January. (Folder 62: 7)
  - "Present Day Political Discussions," 1944 March. (Folder 62: 8)
    Typescript. Includes writing on Soviet plans concerning Europe and Great Britain, Russia and Japan, etc.
  - "The Slovak Rising: A Patriotic Movement and Its Background," Weekly Newspaper and Review, London, 1944 September 23. (Folder 62: 9)
  - Letters to the editor, The News Chronicle, 1944. (Folder 62: 10)
  - "Czech Revolt Against Beneš's Government," 1945? (Folder 62: 11)
    Typescript. Includes typescript of a speech by R. Bechyně at a Czechoslovak political meeting held in London, 1945 January 19, and text of resolution of the Czechoslovak citizens assembled at the meeting
  - Untitled writing on beginning of the United Nations, 1945 (Folder 62: 12)
  - Speech addressed to American Slovak national organizations in the United States, London, 1945 January 15. (Folder 62: 13)
  - "Foreign Affairs and Slovakia," speech, meeting of Czechoslovak citizens, Kingsway Hall, Holborn, London, 1945 February 14. (Folder 62: 14)
  - Lecture, Allied Circle, Dumbarton Oaks, 1945 May 7. (Folder 62: 15)
  - Untitled writing on the Nuremberg Trial, 1946. (Folder 62: 16)
    Holograph, clippings
  - Radio discussion with Louis Gottschalk and John Scott, Europe's Political Future, University of Chicago Round Table, Chicago, 1946 April 21. (Folder 62: 17)
  - "The Russian Quest for European Unity," speech, The Creighton Club, 1946 November 2-3. (Folder 62: 18)
  - "Czechoslovakia's Founders," The New York Times, 1947 August 9. (Folder 62: 19)
  - Letters to the editor, The New York Times, 1947-1964. (Folder 62: 20)
  - Speech on international affairs, The Trade Union Advisory Committee, 1948 January 6. (Folder 62: 21)
  - "Europe's Golden Chance," Freedom and Union, 1948 February. (Folder 62: 22)
  - "East-West Crisis Made Certain in 1945" and "Kremlin Disposes of Embarrassing Genetics," The Washington Post, 1948 August 15 and 29. (Folder 62: 23)
  - "Soviet Russia's Challenge to America," address, Annual Meeting of the National Institute of Social Sciences, New York, 1949 February 10. (Folder 62: 24)
  - "The Challenge of World Trends to American Management Statesmanship," paper, Midwinter Personnel Conference of the American Management Association, Chicago, Illinois, 1949 February 14-16. (Folder 62: 25)
  - "The Atlantic Pact," lecture, Colgate University, 1949 March 1. (Folder 62: 26)
  - "Soviet Challenge to America," radio address, ABC Network, 1949 March 27. (Folder 62: 27)
  - "The Agricultural Problem in the Satellite Countries," The Polish Review, 1949 November. (Folder 62: 28)
  - "America's Ultimatum to Europe," lecture, Colgate University, 1949 November 8. (Folder 62: 29)
  - "Industrialization and the Middle Class Behind the Iron Curtain," Našim v Exilu, Paris, 1949 December. (Box-folder 63: 1)
    Holograph, typescript, and printed copy
  - "Silný střední stav zaručuje stabilitu evropské demokracie," Novina, 1950. (Folder 63: 2)
    Printed copy (in Czech)
  - "Věrní zůstaneme," speech, Colgate University, 1950 February 23. (Folder 63: 3)
  - "La coopération germano-russe dans le passé et ses perspectives actuelles," 1950 April 8. (Folder 63: 4)
  - "Form Follows Function," paper, Thirty-First Annual Session of the Southern Industrial Relations Conference, Blue Ridge, North Carolina, 1950 July 19-22. (Folder 63: 5)
  - "Labour Situation in Czechoslovakia," radio address broadcast, London, 1950 August. (Folder 63: 6)
  - Reflections on Noel Sargent's speech "Economic Freedom in an Age of Science," 1950 August 2. (Folder 63: 7)
    Holograph and typescript. Includes a letter from Noel Sargent
  - "United Nations Day at Hartford," speech, Horace Bushnell Memorial Hall, Connecticut, 1950 October 27. (Folder 63: 8)
  - The Way of the Free, E. P. Dutton, New York, 1951
    - Notes (on the pursuit of happpiness, Russian constants, world order in the making)
    - Holograph (Folder 63: 10)
    - Typescript (partial) (Folder 63: 11)
    - Reviews (Folder 63: 12-13)
    - Correspondence, including with publisher E. P. Dutton & Co., Inc., 1949-1953 (Folder 63: 14-15)
  - "A House Divided Can Not Stand," speech, Independence Hall, Philadelphia, 1951 February 11. (Box-folder 64: 1)
    Notes and typescript (in English and Slovak)
  - "Realism in the Schuman Plan," Washington Post, 1951 March 25. (Folder 64: 2)
  - "Czech Expert Finds Schuman Plan 'A Decisive Step' to Federation," The Federalist, 1951 April. (Folder 64: 3)
  - "Is Peace Possible Between The United States and Russia?" commencement speech, Hamline University, Saint Paul, Minnesota, 1951 June 4. (Folder 64: 4)
  - "Central-Eastern Europe," Foreign Affairs, 1951 October. (Folder 64: 5)
  - "Comité Français pour l'Europe Libre," 1952? (Folder 64: 6)
    Holograph and typescript (in English)
  - Speech, Symposium on Liberation and Union: The Future of Danubian Federation and the Atlantic Union, Freedom & Union, Washington, D.C., 1952. (Folder 64: 7)
  - "Prominenti v exilu," New Year's speech broadcast, Radio Free Europe, 1952 January 1. (Folder 64: 8)
  - "Memorandum [on the risks of a 'German Munich' and a 'Russian Munich']," 1952 April 8. (Folder 64: 9)
  - "Slovak National Insurrection," speech, 1952 August. (Folder 64: 10)
  - "Učinok reči generála Eisenhowera na verejnu mienku v ČSR," 1952 September 7. (Folder 64: 11)
  - Speech on the unification of Europe, Radio Free Europe, 1952 September 30. (Folder 64: 12)
  - "Fluidity Behind the Iron Curtain: Source of Diplomatic Victory or Defeat," 1953 February 10. (Folder 64: 13)
  - "Political Warfare," 1953 March 7. (Folder 64: 14)
  - Interview with Národní střed, 1953 April. (Folder 64: 15)
  - Speech, Forum of Freedom: How to Capitalize on the Soviet Interregnum? (Four Eastern European Leaders in Exile Advance Proposals), Freedom & Union, 1953 April. (Folder 64: 16)
  - "Our Tasks and Aims," speech, Meeting of the Central Committee of the Council of Free Czechoslovakia, New York City, 1953 May 23. (Folder 64: 17)
    Typescript (in English and Czech)
  - "Making the Points," note on the Korean problem, 1953 July 4. (Folder 64: 18)
  - "Conference of Three Foreign Ministers," 1953 July 18. (Folder 64: 19)
  - "The Riddle of Prosperity," New York Herald Tribune, 1953 July 28. (Folder 64: 20)
  - Letters to the editor, The Washington Post, 1953-1963. (Folder 64: 21)
  - "Byla to politická msta a zločin," Agrární politika, 1954. (Folder 64: 22)
  - Speech, 30th Anniversary of the death of Woodrow Wilson, Carnegie Hall, New York City, 1954 February 3. (Folder 64: 23)
  - "Forced Labor in Czechoslovakia," statement, New York, 1954 April 14. (Folder 64: 24)
  - Speech, Tirnovo celebration, Library of Congress, Washington, D.C., 1954 April 28. (Folder 64: 25)
  - Speech commemorating Rudolf Beran, Carnegie Hall, New York, 1954 June 10. (Folder 64: 26)
    Typescript (in English and Slovak)
  - Speech commemorating Milan Hodža, Carnegie Endowment International Center, New York, 1954 June 24. (Folder 64: 27)
  - "Prohlášení dr. Štefana Osuského," statement regarding president Eisenhower's offer to ship American food and medical aid to relieve flood suffering in Czechoslovakia, 1954 July 30. (Folder 64: 28)
    Typescript (in Czech) and printed copy of Congressional Record
  - Letter to the Executive Committee of the World Presbytarian Alliance regarding Josef L. Hromádka, official delegate of the Evangelical Church of Czech Brethren to the World Church Congress, 1954 August 2. (Folder 64: 29)
    Printed copy of Congressional Record
  - Speech, Fifty-Second Annual Convention of the International Platform Association, 1954 August 22. (Folder 64: 30)
  - Speech, 36th anniversary of Czechoslovakia's independence, broadcast by Radio Free Europe, 1954 October 28. (Folder 64: 31)
  - Speech, 1955 February 11. (Folder 64: 32)
  - "Coexistence," statement on "What Can the Free World Learn from the Iron Curtain Countries?" ABC Radio Network (series of lectures "Town Hall's Popular Courses" organized in cooperation with the National Committee for Free Europe), 1955 February 20. (Folder 64: 33)
  - "The Future of Europe," 1955 March 13. (Folder 64: 34)
  - Memorandum on the Enslavement of the Central-Eastern European Nations by the Soviet Union, 1955 June 18. (Folder 65: 1)
  - "Úloha Československa v Evrope," speech, Československý Narodný Dom, London, 1955 July 29. (Folder 65: 2)
  - Speech, 37th anniversary of Czechoslovakia's independence, Société de Gymnastique Sokol, Paris, 1955 October 28. (Folder 65: 3)
  - Speech, meeting of the Alliance of Czechoslovak Exiles, Chicago, 1955 November 23. (Folder 65: 4)
    Holograph and clippings (in Slovak)
  - "The Soviet Conception of Law," 1956? (Folder 65: 5-8)
    Notes, holographs, typescripts
  - "Soviet Legal Theory," 1956? (Folder 65: 9)
  - "Communist Law and the Soviet Federation of Nations," 1956 January. (Folder 65: 10)
  - "Liberating the Satellites," 1956 January 23. (Folder 65: 11)
  - "Benjamin Franklin," speech, Radio Free Europe, New York, 1956 February 3. (Box-folder 66: 1)
    Holograph and typescript. Includes publications and speeches relating to the International Celebration of the 250th Anniversary of the Birth of Benjamin Franklin organized by the Franklin Institute in Philadephia during 1955 and 1956
  - "Deklaracija vzájomnej závislosti," speech, Radio Free Europe, New York, 1956 February 3. (Folder 66: 2)
    Holograph and typescript. Includes the Declaration of Interdependence of the Interdependence Council, proclaimed at the Council's conference, held in Philadelphia, January 18, 1956, "Dr. Štefan Osuský's Statement on the Declaration of Interdependence," and clippings
  - "Communication de Monsieur Štefan Osuský à l'Institut d'Etudes Européennes," broadcast transcript, 1956 May 14. (Folder 66: 3)
    Typescript (in French) and clippings
  - Report on the 6th Congress of the International Association of Democratic Lawyers, Brussels, 1956 May 22-25. (Folder 66: 4)
  - Speech, Československý Národný Dom, London, 1956 May 26. (Folder 66: 5)
  - "Tito's Communism," 1956 July. (Folder 66: 6)
  - "Potentialities of Western Strategy Towards the Communist Ruled Countries," 1956 October 8. (Folder 66: 7)
  - "La jurisprudence dans les démocraties populaires," Conference, Académie des Sciences Morales et Politiques, Institut de France, Paris, 1956 October 15. (Folder 66: 8)
    Notes (in English and Slovak) and typescript (in French). Includes correspondence with Emil Mireaux and Ph. Brissand (in French) and clippings
  - Lecture, London, 1956 October 26. (Folder 66: 9)
  - Speech, opening session of the International Peasant Union, Paris, 1956 October 28. (Folder 66: 10)
  - "Le processus de déstalinisation amorce une réaction en chaîne," La Tribune de Genève, 1956 November 9. (Folder 66: 11)
  - "Red Assault on Hungary Scored by Hague Jurists," The New York Herald Tribune, 1956 December 11. (Folder 66: 12)
  - Letters to the editor, The Evening Star, 1956-1957. (Folder 66: 13)
  - "Le droit du contrat en Bulgarie, Tchécoslovaquie, Hongrie, Pologne et Roumanie," French translation of a lecture delivered at the Library of Congress, Washington, D.C., 1957. (Folder 66: 14)
  - Speech delivered at the launching of the Crusade for Freedom, Saint Paul, Minnesota, 1957 February 9. (Folder 66: 15)
  - "The Quest for a New World Equilibrium," lecture, the Allied Circle, London, 1957 May 16. (Box-folder 67: 1)
  - "Europská rada," Hlas exilu, 1957 June 1. (Folder 67: 2)
  - Review of Suzanne Labin, "Les entretiens de Saint-Germain: Liberté aux liberticides?" Western World, 1957 September 12. (Folder 67: 3)
    Holograph and typescript (in English). Includes a copy of Suzanne Labin's "Ambassades pour subversions"
  - Review of Jeanne Hersh, "Idéologies et réalités," Western World, 1957 September 23. (Folder 67: 4)
  - Letters to the editor, The Christian Science Monitor, 1957-1967. (Folder 67: 5)
  - "Komunistická propaganda k 40. výročiu ČSR pripisuje zásluhu o jej vznik Leninovi a Sovietom," 1958. (Folder 67: 6)
  - "Czechoslovakia: A Warning," 1958 February 18. (Folder 67: 7)
  - "Peaceful Co-Existence: Popular Fronts and Economic Competition," speech, Kosciusko Foundation, New York, 1958 March 7. (Folder 67: 8)
  - Speech delivered at the meeting of the Interdependence Council, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1958 March 17. (Folder 67: 9)
  - "Pražskí komunisti falšujú historiu," 1958 October? (Folder 67: 10)
  - "Events Leading to Munich: Beneš Said to Have Offered Czech Territory to Hitler," The New York Times, 1958 October 9. (Folder 67: 11)
  - "The Fortieth Anniversary of Czechoslovakia," 1958 October 28. (Folder 67: 12)
  - "Beneš's Career Praised," The New York Times, 1958 November 21. (Folder 67: 13)
  - "Nečekal jsem dvacet let," 1959? (Folder 67: 14)
  - Letters to the editor, Cas, 1959. (Folder 67: 15)
  - "The Paris Economic Conference," Washington, D.C., 1960 February 22. (Folder 67: 16)
  - "Atlantic Economic Community in Process of Being Born," 1960 March 10. (Folder 67: 17)
  - "Soviet Attitude in the Munich Crisis," speech, annual meeting of the International Free Academy of Sciences and Letters, New York, 1960 March 26. (Folder 67: 18)
  - "Postwar Economic Trends: Soviet, British, European, U.S.," Freedom & Union, 1960 September. (Folder 67: 19)
  - "Encirclement of the 'Capitalist Countries' by the Soviets," lecture, the Allied Circle, 1961 April 6, The Allied Circle Journal. (Folder 67: 20)
    Notes, typescript, clippings, and printed copy